This channel, smaller channel,
is business to business.
I am trying to sell to other businesses,
and I am really playing business on easy
mode.
A lot of people in my position fuck you up
mentally, and I'll explain why.
So I know it's not a sexy term.
We have business to business, and we have
business to consumer. So here,
you're selling yoga, you're
selling workouts,
you're selling a 12-pack of Nutonic. Cool.
B2B, I sell my mentorship. I sell,
let's say,
courses on how to make content.
People like me on YouTube, we talk about
the revenue we make. We have 100K months.
Yeah,
45 of it's gone in paid ads alone because
they do work
over here. Then I got staff,
then I got costs,
then whatever I do get at the end of
that, government takes half.
It's not all as impressive as you think.
But it's actually very easy to make paid
ads work on this ecosystem.
It's incredibly difficult on here.
But business coaches,
they keep those things a little bit
conflated.
Same way I'll talk in revenue like it's
profit when it's not,
and I'll talk as paid
ad strategy like it's going to work for
you when it won't.
The first consideration, I would say,
is who's paying?
As in, is it you or the business?
Because that makes a big
difference. Because
when we're selling something here,
let's say we're selling
greens powder. For B2C,
for an individual to buy that,
they have to pay
income tax,
and then they've got their little pot of
money that's left at the end.
Whereas someone who's buying it through a
business, their business is paying for
it, so it's a business investment.
Over here, B2C,
there's not a return on investment.
Well, you might get more mobile from yoga,
you might get more spirulina in your
diet from the greens powder,
you might lock in during Nutonic.
But when it's a B2B,
there's a return on investment.
So the intent of the purchaser
is more likely to spend $1,000 here
because then it
makes some back. Whereas over here,
they're just buying a consumer product.
Now, another consideration
is going to be markup.
Now, a lot of these products that
are incredibly expensive, like the big
popular greens powder
that we all know about
that sponsors everything online,
they're only so expensive so they can get
that markup involved.
So I would say their paid ads are working,
but it's an extortionate amount, and
they have to use a lot of influencer
marketing to do it.
But the main problem here
is the same way that these people will
conflate their
revenue with profit,
they conflate their paid ads.
I can make paid ads work for the business
mentorship because we're selling
something that's at an insane margin,
and it's at an insane margin because
people
get a return on investment.
So do you think most of those people who
have got paid ads, like all the personal
trainers or random fuckers
that just keep hitting you with paid ads,
are they
actually making profit out of that, or
is it just a-
Very rarely.
Now, the issue here
is the majority of B2C ads
just do not work. So people
are wasting money, and they're hoping
that eventually
they're going to turn a profit
and they're going to get their whatever.
But the other issue is,
let's think about wherever we want to
get impressions,
we have to pay for it one
or the other way.
We either pay for it or we give time.
Now, everyone trying to sell you ads
and be like, "Oh my God,
I get two shares a
day." Oh, don't waste your time.
Let's pay for it instead.
However, one of the key things
that people don't talk about
is to get impressions,
you can get them for free as long as
you're good at content.
So people that aren't good at content,
one of them pay for ads.
But if you're not good at content
and you pay for a video to see someone
and it's
not a good video,
it's not really going to relate to them.
Also,
let's say you want to work on impressions
and clicks.
What do you think is going to perform
better?
Someone you've paid to see your offer to
land on your landing page, or someone that
you've spent time nurturing,
creating content for,
and sitting in front of your
content for hours? Here,
they decide to click on your offer because
they feel like
they're there. Here,
you're just in front of them so much
they're like, "Oh, let's
have a look at this." So these
are very different people
that come down either
channel here, and people
are incredibly disingenuous with this.
Now-
Do you think the paid ads,
there's going to be fatigue over time as
well?
Oh, yeah. We have to change the backdrops.
We can't do ads in this room anymore
because the gray backdrops, we've already
diminished and fatigued those.
What about as a whole?
Do you think paid ads
are going to become less and less
effective, or it's just-
Paid ads will always play a part,
but the issue is here.
Let's say you're my client,
you're brand new.
You go, "James, I've got $100,000.
I want to get a billion impressions." I'd
probably say the quickest way to do it is
to pay. But if you came back, same budget,
and you wanted 10 million impressions,
I'd say we're going to have to go organic.
You haven't got enough money for us to get
the impressions that we want.
But if you give me a year
and you get good enough at making content,
and you get
big enough ecosystem,
you can get those impressions organically.
I think organic is always the best thing
because everyone out there is shit at
making videos, they're shit at marketing,
and they've got no audience.
So all of our competitors
are burning through investors' cash to pay
for the exact same places that we are.
So whilst we're out there,
we're very fortunate
that we have Chris and I to promote
the products. All of our competitors,
the only thing they can do is pay.
So they're booking the exact same slots we
are, which is driving up the cost of
ads. The cake is your organic.
The icing is the paid.
If you have a solid cake like a Victoria
sponge, something that doesn't need icing,
it's going to be absolutely cool.
You want to do paid on top? Cool.
I'll even give you a little candle.
But so many people think
that they can just arrive
and pay their way through it,
and they're just going to burn money.
Like you say,
all those personal trainers
and all those ads that you're seeing,
people are probably burning money
that they got fucking inherited,
or they've saved
up for years in a corporate job thinking
they can buy their way out.
And it's a really, really sad place.
Me, the only business I run ads that
are profitable is in B2B,
and even some months we'll only hit a
ROAS, which is a return on ad
spend, of 1.4,
which means for every $100 we spend,
we make
$140.
But considering because we've got staff,
we've got costs, we've got to deal
with Gem for everything. If that hits 1.1,
1.2, I'm losing money.
So I finished the month, I made 150K,
and suddenly the
50K we've spent on ads, my bill
is going to be 60.
So because of all the other costs that
are incurred.
So I pretty much need to hit a 1.8 ROAS
just to be in the green,
which is a lot of pressure.
So a lot of the time,
everyone online that's trying to
teach you paid ads,
they just want your money. "Hey, Declan,
pay us five grand.
We'll run ads for you."
And they're just going to go, "Oh, sorry,
the ads aren't
working. Maybe send us more creatives.
Tell you what, double the budget
and we might be able to get some more ad
spend."
But the craziest thing is,
the thing that's the saddest thing here
is it's just a
horrible distraction
that people fall into,
and they spend thousands of dollars
with these agencies trying to get their
ads to work, when really, if they had just
put all that time, energy,
and effort into buying a nice camera,
renting an office
for six months,
they could've sat in it
and churned out enough content.
And ultimately,
what people don't like to admit
is at the end of the day, they're
just looking for an easy way out. Oh,
wouldn't it be nice for me to just spend
money to not have to do the fucking hard
work?
And if it was that easy,
I wouldn't be making videos.
I wouldn't be here right now.
If I could just pay my way to more clients
to not have to put out organic.
And another thing that I told you earlier,
do you know what really makes paid ads
work?
When people have seen hours of your
organic.
The only reason that I get probably even
the 1.8 ROAS is because
the people we're serving ads to have seen
my content before.
There is no way that you don't pay with
time.
Alex Hormozi,
still putting out fucking 100 videos a
week.
The cunt's got hundreds of millions.
Steven Bartlett,
still doing three pods a week.
The guy's got fucking millions.
If you could just pay your way,
these guys would have kicked up, retired,
and done
everything themselves.
Hormozi does do a lot in paid,
but he does a fuckload in
organic as well.
Call this the cake system.
You can have organic without paid,
but you cannot have paid without organic.